About

32 years old Zwanenveld 9150 6538 S.I.NLIMEGEN THE NETHERLANDS **1** (+31) 6 30607282 ■ benoit@viguier.nl ☆ viguier.nl in beviguier **y** @ildyria ☐ ildyria

Language

French ****

English ★★★★

Spanish ★★★★★ Japanese ★★★★

Dutch ★★★★★ German ★★★★★



I am currently writting my PhD Thesis on Cryptography and Formal Verification. I am passionate about symmetric cryptography, formal methods, and beautiful code. I am also a competitive ballroom dancer and a photographer.

Education

Software Engineer INSA (NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF APPLIED SCIENCES)

MRes. in Computer Science University Rennes 1

MSc. in Mathematics

UNIVERSITY RENNES 1

Skills

Rennes, France Sept. 2014 - 2016

Rennes, France Sept. 2015 - 2016

Rennes. France

Sept. 2006 - 2011

Programming C/C++, Coq, Python, RISC-V asm, ARM Asm, PHP. MEX **Dev. Env.** Visual Studio Code, IntelliJ IDEA, Clion, PhpStorm, Git, Atom

OS Preference

Debian ★★★★★ Windows ★★★★ MacOs ★★★★★

Experience _____

PhD Candidate

RADBOUD UNIVERSITY

- Designing symmetric cryptography algorithm.
- · Writting optimized implementation for lightweight schemes.
- Using formal methods to verify cryptographic C implementations.

Coq, Formal Approaches, Cryptanalysis, C, Assembly

Ballroom Dancing Photography Piano Rock climbing Martial Arts

Activities

Sailing

Internship: Software Engineer & Researcher

STMICROELECTRONICS

- Verification of the truncated tree search using Formal Methods.
- · Application to differential and linear trail search.

Coq, C++, Differential Cryptanalysis, Hash functions

Nijmegen, The Netherlands

Brussels, Belgium Feb. - Jun. 2016

Sep. 2016 - Dec. 2020

Internship: Software Engineer

MISSION CRITICAL IT

• SNOMED CT, ICD10PCS and NLP parsing.

Lucene, OpenNLP, Stanford Parser, SWRL, Ontologies, JAVA

Brussels, Belgium

Jun. - Sep. 2015

Mathematics Teacher

· Junior Highschool and Highschool

Teamwork, teaching skills, formalism

2011 - 2014

Publications

FEBRUARY 18, 2021

A Cog proof of the correctness of X25519 in TweetNaCl

Dubrovnik

34TH IEEE COMPUTER SECURITY FOUNDATIONS SYMPOSIUM

Jun. 2021

· We formally prove that the C implementation of the X25519 key-exchange protocol in the TweetNaCl library correctly implements the protocol from Bernstein's 2006 paper, as standardized in RFC 7748, as well as the absence of the standardized in RFC 1748 and 1948 are the standardized in RFC 1748, as well as the absence of the standardized in RFC 1748 and 1949 are the standardized in RFC 1748 are the standardized in RFC 1748 and 1949 are the standardized in RFC 1748 are the standardizedundefined behavior. We also formally prove that X25519 is mathematically correct, i.e., that it correctly computes scalar multiplica- tion on the elliptic curve Curve25519. The proofs are all computer-verified using Coq.

Assembly or Optimized C for Lightweight Cryptography on RISC-V?

Vienna

CRYPTOLOGY AND NETWORK SECURITY

Dec. 2020

• In this work, we studied the general impact of optimizing symmetric-key algorithms in assembly and in plain C on RISC-V architectures. Additionally, we present optimized implementations of NIST's lightweight candidates, with speed-ups of up to 81% over available implementations, and discuss general implementation strategies.

Cryptanalysis of MORUS

Brisbane, Australia

ADVANCES IN CRYPTOLOGY - ASIACRYPT 2018, LNCS

Dec. 2018

• We present a linear correlation in the keystream of full MORUS, which can be used to distinguish its output from random and to recover some plaintext bits in the broadcast setting.

KangarooTwelve: fast hashing based on Keccak-p

Leuven, Belgium

APPLIED CRYPTOGRAPHY AND NETWORK SECURITY - ACNS 2018, LNCS

July 2018

 KangarooTwelve, a fast and secure arbitrary output-length hash function aiming at a higher speed than the FIPS 202's SHA-3 and SHAKE functions.

Gimli: A Cross-Platform Permutation

Taipei, Taiwan

CRYPTOGRAPHIC HARDWARE AND EMBEDDED SYSTEMS - CHES 2017, LNCS

Sept. 2017

 Gimli, a 384-bit permutation designed to achieve high security with high performance across a broad range of platforms.

Extra Activities

DSV Sway of Life

The Netherlands
Mar. 2018 - PRESENT

STANDARD BALLROOM FORMATION DANCER

- ullet 2020 $ullet^{th}$ place Dutch Championship in couple C-class Standard Dalfsen
- 2019 1st place Dutch Championship in Formation Dancing Almere
- 2019 **Finalist** World Championship in Formation Dancing Moskow
- 2018 $\mathbf{1}^{st}$ place Dutch Championship in Formation Dancing Almere

Landscapes & Ballroom Photography

The Netherlands

PHOTOGRAPHER

Jul. 2018 - PRESENT

- Landscapes & long exposures
- Ballroom Photography WDSF, NADB, NTDS, ETDS
- Events PhD Defenses
- PortraitureLycheeOrg

The Netherlands

Main Developer & Administrator

Aug. 2018 - PRESENT

• Complete rewrite of the Lychee image server with Laravel.